Register of the Charles Easton Rothwell papers, 1924-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
Charles Easton Rothwell papers
1924-1995
90005
Hoover Institution Archives
75 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 10 envelopes, 1 album, 5 maps, 9 sound cassettes (37.7 linear feet)
Writings, correspondence, memoranda, reports, printed matter, photographs, and sound recordings relating to the United Nations, American foreign policy (especially in Asia), promotion of the study of international relations, and administration and activities of the Hoover Institution, Stanford University, Mills College, the Asia Foundation, and the National War College.
Rothwell, Charles Easton, 1902-1987.
Access
Boxes are stored off site; a minimum of two days notice is required for use. Boxes may be requested through Stanford's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1990.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/ Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1902 October 9 Born, Denver, Colorado
1924 A.B., Reed College, Portland, Oregon
1927-1932 Director, Teacher Training in Social Sciences, University of Oregon
1929 A.M., University of Oregon
1930 Author (with Alfred N. Lomax), An Economic Geography of the Oregon Region
1932 Married Virginia Sterling, Santa Monica, California
1932-1939 Instructor, Citizenship and History, Stanford University
1938 Ph.D., Stanford University
1939-1941 Assistant Professor, History, and Advisor, Reed College
1941-1946 Worked with the Department of State, United States Government
1941 Contributor, "War and Economic Institutions," War as a Social Institution, American Historical Association
1945 Executive Secretary, United Nations Conference International Organization, San Francisco, California
1946 Secretary General, U.S. delegation to United Nations
1946-1947 Senior staff member, Brookings Institution
1947-1952 Vice Chairman and Research Professor, Hoover Institution and Library
1949 Contributor, "International Organization and World Politics," International Organization, Vol. III Contributor, "International Relations in a World of Change," World Politics
1951 Staff member, National War College Contributor, The Policy Sciences, edited by Daniel Lerner and Harold Lasswell
1952 Author (with H. D. Laswell and D. Lerner), A Comparative Study of Elites
1952-1959 Director, Hoover Institution
1954 Contributor, "Europe in the Post War Period," Introduction to International Relations
1959-1967 President, Mills College, Oakland, California
1987 May 1 Died, Marin County, California
Scope and Content of Collection
Writings, correspondence, memoranda, reports, printed matter, photographs, and sound recordings relating to the United Nations, American foreign policy (especially in Asia), promotion of the study of international relations, and administration and activities of the Hoover Institution, Stanford University, Mills College, the Asia Foundation, and the National War College.
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace.; Mills College.; National War College (U.S.); Stanford University.; United Nations Conference on International Organization (1945: San Francisco, Calif.); United Nations.; United States. Dept. of State.; Asia--Foreign relations--United States.; Asia.; Education.; International education.; United States--Foreign relations--1945-1989.; United States--Foreign relations--Asia.; United States--Foreign relations.; Universities and colleges--United States.; World War, 1939-1945--United States.; World War, 1939-1945.
- Biographical File, 1924-1989 (Box 1-4)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes applications and registration forms, biographical notes, brochures, bulletins, certificates, clippings, correspondence, financial records, flyers, interview, invitations, list of charitable contributions made in the memory of Charles Easton Rothwell, membership records, memoranda, minutes of meeting, notes, pamphlets, press releases, printed matter and articles written about Rothwell, and records relating to his involvement in the community, as well as the poems written by him and others, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Application and registration forms (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Biographical notes (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Brochures (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Bulletins (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Certificates (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Clippings (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Correspondence (Box-folder 1: 7)
    Includes letters written to and by Virginia Rothwell.
  - Financial records (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Interview (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Invitations (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Membership records (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Memoranda (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Minutes of meeting (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Newsletters (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Notes (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Pamphlets (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Personnel file (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Press releases (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Printed matter (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Programs (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Subject file
    - Community service
      - Point Reyes National Seashore and the Community of Inverness
        - General (Box-folder 2: 11)
        - Correspondence (Box-folder 2: 12)
        - Master plan (Box-folder 2: 13)
        - Memoranda (Box-folder 2: 14)
        - Minutes of meetings (Box-folder 2: 15)
        - Notes (Box-folder 2: 16)
        - Statements (Box-folder 2: 17)
          Includes statements of others.
        - Study (Box-folder 2: 18)
      - Town of Los Altos Hills
        - General (Box-folder 2: 19)
        - Articles and clippings (Box-folder 2: 20)
        - Bulletins (Box-folder 2: 21)
        - Correspondence (Box-folder 2: 22)
        - Flyers (Box-folder 2: 23)
        - Map (Box-folder 2: 24)
        - Memoranda (Box-folder 2: 25)
        - Minutes of meetings
          - 1956 (Box-folder 2: 26)
          - 1957
            - January-July (Box-folder 2: 27)
            - August-November (Box-folder 2: 28)
        - Ordinances (Box-folder 2: 29)
        - Reports (Box-folder 2: 30)
        - Statements (Box-folder 2: 31)
        - Study (Box-folder 2: 32)
    - Funeral
      - Articles and clippings (Box-folder 3: 1)
      - Book of mourners (Box-folder 3: 2)
      - Book plate (Box-folder 3: 3)
      - Bulletins (Box-folder 3: 4)
      - Cards of sympathy (Box-folder 3: 5-6)
      - Correspondence
        - Undated (Box-folder 3: 7)
        - 1987
          - April (Box-folder 3: 8)
          - May (Box-folder 3: 9-10)
          - June (Box-folder 4: 1)
          - July (Box-folder 4: 2)
          - September (Box-folder 4: 3)
          - November-December (Box-folder 4: 4)
      - Death certificate (Box-folder 4: 5)
      - List
        Charitable contributions made by others in memory of Charles Easton Rothwell.
        - General (Box-folder 4: 6)
        - Mills College (Box-folder 4: 7)
        - Reed College (Box-folder 4: 8)
      - Memorial program (Box-folder 4: 9)
      - Notes (Box-folder 4: 10)
      - Printed matter (Box-folder 4: 11)
    - Poetry
      Written by Charles Easton Rothwell and others.
      - General (Box-folder 4: 12)
      - 1961-1972 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Telegrams (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - Writings about Charles Easton Rothwell (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - Miscellany (Box-folder 4: 16)
- Correspondence, 1933-1982 (Box 4-9)
  Letters, arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Includes letters neither from nor to Charles Easton Rothwell.
  - Undated (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - Unidentified (Box-folder 4: 18)
  - A. N. Marquis Company, 1948-1965 (Box-folder 4: 19)
  - Acheson, Dean, 1947 (Box-folder 4: 20)
  - Albert, Alexander, Mrs., 1965 (Box-folder 4: 21)
  - Allen, Charles E., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 4: 22)
  - Ammen, Paul V., 1967 (Box-folder 4: 23)
  - Anderson, John B., 1976 (Box-folder 4: 24)
  - Anderson, Robert, Mr. and Mrs., 1955 (Box-folder 4: 25)
  - Anderson, Signe, 1967 (Box-folder 4: 26)
  - Andrews, William S., 1967 (Box-folder 4: 27)
  - Angelo, Homer G., 1940 (Box-folder 4: 28)
  - Armsey, James W., 1967 (Box-folder 4: 29)
  - Ashton, Sherley, 1966 (Box-folder 4: 30)
  - Aufhauser, Stefanie, 1966 (Box-folder 4: 31)
  - Balibanoff, Angelica, 1939 (Box-folder 4: 32)
  - Barbour, Tom, 1970 (Box-folder 4: 33)
  - Barker, Charles A., 1947 (Box-folder 4: 34)
  - Barker, S. Leonard, Mr. and Mrs., 1964 (Box-folder 4: 35)
  - Barker, W. Gardner, III, Mr. and Mrs., 1955-1965 (Box-folder 4: 36)
  - Barnhart, Edward N., 1949 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Barry, David G., 1967 (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Barton, Rollie E., Mrs., 1967 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Beaver, Clayton J., Jr., 1962-1967 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Bechtel, S. D., 1974 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Beise, Clark, 1957 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Bellquist, Eric C., 1966 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Benson, Robert L., II, 1967 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Berdahl, Clarence A., 1949 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Bergquist, Martha, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Biggerrteff, John, 1974 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Bird, Grace, 1949 (Box-folder 5: 12)
  - Bird, Remsen Du Bois, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 5: 13)
  - Blachly, Dan, 1966 (Box-folder 5: 14)
  - Blackwelder, Justin, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 5: 15)
  - Bohemian Club, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 5: 16)
  - Booth, Arch N., 1951 (Box-folder 5: 17)
  - Bowes, Watson E., Mr. and Mrs., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - Braisted, Paul J., 1966 (Box-folder 5: 19)
  - Brawner, Fuller, 1968 (Box-folder 5: 20)
  - Brett, James Q., 1964 (Box-folder 5: 21)
  - Briggs, Mitchell P., 1961-1963 (Box-folder 5: 22)
  - Brinton, William M., 1962 (Box-folder 5: 23)
  - Brockway, Tom, 1967 (Box-folder 5: 24)
  - Brooke, Jim, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 5: 25)
  - Brown, Arnold B., Mrs., 1949 (Box-folder 5: 26)
  - Brown, Belford, 1949 (Box-folder 5: 27)
  - Brown, Bob, 1967 (Box-folder 5: 28)
  - Brown, Dyke, 1955-1967 (Box-folder 5: 29)
  - Brown, Edmund G., 1962-1966 (Box-folder 5: 30)
  - Brown, Seyon, 1976 (Box-folder 5: 31)
  - Browning, George, 1949 (Box-folder 5: 32)
  - Bruheim, Frank, 1966 (Box-folder 5: 33)
  - Brundage, Avery, 1966 (Box-folder 5: 34)
  - Bullis, Gardner, Mr. and Mrs., 1967 (Box-folder 5: 35)
  - Bungey, Grace R., 1949 (Box-folder 5: 36)
  - Burdette, Franklin L., 1962 (Box-folder 5: 37)
  - Burgess, Carter L., 1949-1957 (Box-folder 5: 38)
  - Burk, Marguerite C., 1937 (Box-folder 5: 39)
  - Burn, Jennifer, 1964 (Box-folder 5: 40)
  - Burn, June, 1966 (Box-folder 5: 41)
  - Burnett, Sidney, Mrs., 1967 (Box-folder 5: 42)
  - Burns, Robert, 1955 (Box-folder 5: 43)
  - Bush, Robert, 1949 (Box-folder 5: 44)
  - Carolou, Mary C., 1967 (Box-folder 5: 45)
  - Carpenter, Alfred S. V., Mr. and Mrs., 1965 (Box-folder 5: 46)
  - Carson, Paul and Frances, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 5: 47)
  - Carter, Edward W., 1974 (Box-folder 5: 48)
  - Casassa, Charles S., 1967 (Box-folder 5: 49)
  - Caulkins, Robert, 1967 (Box-folder 5: 50)
  - Chambrun, Rene de, 1959 (Box-folder 5: 51)
  - Chapman, Mary P., 1967 (Box-folder 5: 52)
  - Cheever, Daniel S., 1949 (Box-folder 5: 53)
  - Chenery, William L., 1951 (Box-folder 5: 54)
  - Cherrington, Ben M., 1949-1967 (Box-folder 5: 55)
  - Chittick, V. L. O., Mr. and Mrs., 1967 (Box-folder 5: 56)
  - Chookasian, Babken Levon, 1972 (Box-folder 5: 57)
  - Clapham, L., 1939 (Box-folder 5: 58)
  - Clapp, Norton, 1955 (Box-folder 5: 59)
  - Coldiron, Gene O., 1967 (Box-folder 5: 60)
  - Collins, Anne, 1966 (Box-folder 5: 61)
  - Compton, Wilson, 1955 (Box-folder 5: 62)
  - Condliffe, John B., 1979 (Box-folder 5: 63)
  - Coonan, Terence, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 64)
  - Coons, Arthur G., 1967 (Box-folder 5: 65)
  - Coughlin, Bernard J., 1975 (Box-folder 5: 66)
  - Counselman, Lee, Mrs., 1967 (Box-folder 5: 67)
  - Cowles, Leonard R., 1967 (Box-folder 5: 68)
  - Cox, James, 1949 (Box-folder 5: 69)
  - Cranston, Alan, 1965 (Box-folder 5: 70)
  - Crawford, Greene A., 1964 (Box-folder 5: 71)
  - Davis, Malcolm W., 1948 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Dean, George M., 1966 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Degras, Jane, 1954 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Deimel, Arthur, 1967 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - Detmold, John Hunter, 1967 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Dillon, Jane, 1967 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Donohoe, Patrick A., 1967 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Dowrie, George W., 1949 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Doxiadis, C. A., 1966 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Drake, James F., 1963 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - DuBridge, Lee A., 1966 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Dullea, Charles W., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - Dunbar, Maygene, 1939 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - Eagleton, Clyde, 1949 (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - Eddington, Robert V., 1974 (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - Eddy, Edward D., 1966 (Box-folder 6: 16)
  - Education and World Affairs, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 6: 17)
  - Elliott, Robert C., 1967 (Box-folder 6: 18)
  - Elton, Frank, 1955 (Box-folder 6: 19)
  - Evans, Philip M., 1967 (Box-folder 6: 20)
  - Fackt, Elizabeth L., 1949 (Box-folder 6: 21)
  - Fahey, Daniel, 1949 (Box-folder 6: 22)
  - Falch, Lynn B., 1967 (Box-folder 6: 23)
  - Farley, Hugh D., Mr. and Mrs., 1966 (Box-folder 6: 24)
  - Fawcett, Vance, 1966 (Box-folder 6: 25)
  - Fisher, Cary O., 1967 (Box-folder 6: 26)
  - Fisher, Harold H., Mr. and Mrs., 1951-1967 (Box-folder 6: 27)
  - Fitts, Charles T., Mr. and Mrs., 1967 (Box-folder 6: 28)
  - Fox, William T. R., 1949 (Box-folder 6: 29)
  - Frankel, Charles, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 6: 30)
  - Franklin, George S., Jr., 1966 (Box-folder 6: 31)
  - Frazier, Marie, 1949 (Box-folder 6: 32)
  - Freeman, Gaylord A., Jr., 1964 (Box-folder 6: 33)
  - Fuller, Robert B., 1966 (Box-folder 6: 34)
  - Gabetti, Gianluigi, 1966 (Box-folder 6: 35)
  - Galpin, Perrin C., 1946-1964 (Box-folder 6: 36)
  - Gangs?, John, 1948 (Box-folder 6: 37)
  - Gardner, John W., 1949-1965 (Box-folder 6: 38)
  - Gilliani?, Olive, 1953 (Box-folder 6: 39)
  - Gilman, Richard, 1966 (Box-folder 6: 40)
  - Gilson, Daniel H., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 6: 41)
  - Glide, Mary Ownby, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 6: 42)
  - Glover, Fred, 1982 (Box-folder 6: 43)
  - Goldsen, Joseph M., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 6: 44)
  - Gordon Douglass Boat Co., Inc., 1964 (Box-folder 6: 45)
  - Gould, Charles L., 1963-1965 (Box-folder 6: 46)
  - Graham, William F., 1949 (Box-folder 6: 47)
  - Greene, A. Crawford, 1963 (Box-folder 6: 48)
  - Grether, Ewald T., 1967 (Box-folder 6: 49)
  - Haas, Walter A., 1970-1979 (Box-folder 6: 50)
  - Haehl, Harry L., Jr., 1966 (Box-folder 6: 51)
  - Hagar, Gerald H., 1964 (Box-folder 6: 52)
  - Haizlip, Raymond B., 1974 (Box-folder 6: 53)
  - Halberstadt, Fred J., 1966 (Box-folder 6: 54)
  - Hamilton, James T., Mr. and Mrs., 1949 (Box-folder 6: 55)
  - Hammerly, Paul M., 1964-1966 (Box-folder 6: 56)
  - Hand, H. C., Mr. and Mrs., 1949 (Box-folder 6: 57)
  - Harley Stevens, Georgiana, 1971 (Box-folder 6: 58)
  - Harris, David, Mr. and Mrs., 1967-1974 (Box-folder 6: 59)
  - Hartley, Robert Willard, Mr. and Mrs., 1949-1975 (Box-folder 6: 60)
  - Hatfield, John G., Mrs., 1966 (Box-folder 6: 61)
  - Heggie, Richard G., 1976 (Box-folder 6: 62)
  - Heindel, Richard H., 1949 (Box-folder 6: 63)
  - Hewlett, William R., Mr. and Mrs., 1965 (Box-folder 6: 64)
  - Heyns, Roger W., 1966 (Box-folder 6: 65)
  - Hilbank, Robbins, 1958 (Box-folder 6: 66)
  - Hill, James B., 1966 (Box-folder 6: 67)
  - Hiller, Stanley, 1966 (Box-folder 7: 1)
  - Hopkins, William S., 1967 (Box-folder 7: 2)
  - Houlihan, John C., 1966 (Box-folder 7: 3)
  - House, Kay Seymour, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 4)
  - Howard, Charles, 1964 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Howard, John B., 1967 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Hudson, Samuel W., Jr., Mr. and Mrs., 1965 (Box-folder 7: 7)
  - Humphrey, Ward C., 1967 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - Hunsberger, Warren S., 1955 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - Hutcheson, Austin E., 1949 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - Ike, Nobutake, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 11)
  - Impecoven, Howard, 1966 (Box-folder 7: 12)
  - Inglis, Ruth A., 1949 (Box-folder 7: 13)
  - International Organization, 1949 (Box-folder 7: 14)
  - Israel, Mrs. ?, 1975 (Box-folder 7: 15)
  - Jacobson, David S., 1966 (Box-folder 7: 16)
  - James, Frank G., 1964 (Box-folder 7: 17)
  - Johnson, Herschel V., 1949 (Box-folder 7: 18)
  - Johnson, Joseph E., 1949-1967 (Box-folder 7: 19)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B., 1963 (Box-folder 7: 20)
  - Johnson, Walter, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 21)
  - Jones, Elmer E., Jr., Mr. and Mrs., 1964-1966 (Box-folder 7: 22)
  - Jones, Proctor, 1966 (Box-folder 7: 23)
  - Jong, L. de, 1951 (Box-folder 7: 24)
  - Jonte, J. H., Mrs., 1967 (Box-folder 7: 25)
  - Joukowsky, Martha, 1976 (Box-folder 7: 26)
  - Julie, Catharine, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 7: 27)
  - Justus, Karl B., 1949 (Box-folder 7: 28)
  - Kagon, A. David, Mrs., 1967 (Box-folder 7: 29)
  - Kaiser, Edgar, Mr. and Mrs., 1964-1967 (Box-folder 7: 30)
  - Kaiser, Hannah Jopling, 1974 (Box-folder 7: 31)
  - Keaton, Homer W., 1967 (Box-folder 7: 32)
  - Keep, Winthrop, 1964 (Box-folder 7: 33)
  - Keezer, Dexter M., 1939 (Box-folder 7: 34)
  - Kell, James H., Mrs., 1965 (Box-folder 7: 35)
  - Keller, Gordon, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 36)
  - Kelso, Louis O., 1962 (Box-folder 7: 37)
  - Kerensky, Alexander, 1961 (Box-folder 7: 38)
  - Kerr, Clark, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 7: 39)
  - Kiehly?, A., 1964 (Box-folder 7: 40)
  - King, Edmund T., II, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 41)
  - King, Thomas, Jr., 1967 (Box-folder 7: 42)
  - Kirk, Grayson, 1953-1967 (Box-folder 7: 43)
  - Kirkpatrick, F. A., 1941 (Box-folder 7: 44)
  - Kissane, Leedice, 1966 (Box-folder 7: 45)
  - Knaup, Etta Louise, 1965 (Box-folder 7: 46)
  - Knickerbocker, Paine, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 47)
  - Knight, Max, 1949 (Box-folder 7: 48)
  - Knoll, Cedar, 1951 (Box-folder 7: 49)
  - Knowland, William F., 1964-1966 (Box-folder 7: 50)
  - Kochendoerfer, Violet, 1949 (Box-folder 7: 51)
  - Kolebanova, Janet, 1974 (Box-folder 7: 52)
  - KQED, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 53)
  - Kraushaar, Otto, 1949 (Box-folder 7: 54)
  - Krupp, Marcus A., Mrs., 1966 (Box-folder 7: 55)
  - Kuzell, William Charles, 1935 (Box-folder 7: 56)
  - Lam, Lillie, 1976 (Box-folder 7: 57)
  - Lawrence, Raymond, 1947 (Box-folder 7: 58)
  - Lazard, Claude C., Mrs., 1964 (Box-folder 7: 59)
  - Leavens, Robert, Mrs., 1965 (Box-folder 7: 60)
  - Lee, Gene?, 1966 (Box-folder 7: 61)
  - Lehman, Florence W., 1984 (Box-folder 7: 62)
  - Leonard, J. Paul, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 63)
  - Levy, A. David, 1948 (Box-folder 7: 64)
  - LeVesconte, Ed, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 65)
  - Lindberg, Charles A., 1940 (Box-folder 7: 66)
  - Linsley, Earle G., Mr. and Mrs., 1967 (Box-folder 7: 67)
  - Long, Danielle and Tran, 1975 (Box-folder 7: 68)
  - Lundborg, Louis B., Mr. and Mrs., 1964-1966 (Box-folder 7: 69)
  - Lutz, Ralph Haswell, 1967 (Box-folder 7: 70)
  - McBryde, Duncan, 1965 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - McCaffrey, Stanley E., 1967 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - McCallum, Charles Falconer, Mr. and Mrs., 1965 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - McCarthy, Emmett F., 1951 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - McCulloch, Samuel C., 1967 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - McDonough, John R., Jr., 1959 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - McHenry, Dean E., 1974 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - McKay, Llewellyn, R., 1949-1966 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - McKinley, Charles, 1949-1967 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - McLaughlin, Donald H., 1965-1967 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - McLean, Philip, 1951 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - McNary, Charles, 1940 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - Mackenzie, William G., 1952-1954 (Box-folder 8: 13)
  - MacNaughton, Malcolm, 1965 (Box-folder 8: 14)
  - Mallen, T. Kevin, 1964-1967 (Box-folder 8: 15)
  - Malloch, James M., 1957 (Box-folder 8: 16)
  - Martin, Charles Jr., 1948-1956 (Box-folder 8: 17)
  - Martin, D. Grier, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 18)
  - Martindell, Jackson, 1962 (Box-folder 8: 19)
  - Masland, John, 1949-1957 (Box-folder 8: 20)
  - Mayers, Eugene D., 1967 (Box-folder 8: 21)
  - Mazour, Anatole G., Mrs., 1967 (Box-folder 8: 22)
  - Meiklejohn, Alex, Mr. and Mrs., 1964 (Box-folder 8: 23)
  - Mekrn?, Estelle Knowland, 1972 (Box-folder 8: 24)
  - Merchant, H. J., 1967 (Box-folder 8: 25)
  - Millen, Donna G., 1957 (Box-folder 8: 26)
  - Miller, William J., 1964-1967 (Box-folder 8: 27)
  - Mills, Frederick C., 1937 (Box-folder 8: 28)
  - Monguio, Luis, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 29)
  - Morow?, Bill, 1938 (Box-folder 8: 30)
  - Morris, Brewster, 1952 (Box-folder 8: 31)
  - Mosley, Philip E., 1948-1949 (Box-folder 8: 32)
  - Murphy, Douglas, 1975 (Box-folder 8: 33)
  - Nahas, R. T., 1967 (Box-folder 8: 34)
  - Nason, John W., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 8: 35)
  - National Conference Christians and Jews, 1949 (Box-folder 8: 36)
  - Navapan, Sukum, 1965 (Box-folder 8: 37)
  - Nelson, Albert, 1965 (Box-folder 8: 38)
  - Nesson, Charles R., 1964 (Box-folder 8: 39)
  - Neuman, Sigmund, 1949 (Box-folder 8: 40)
  - Neumeyer, Alfred, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 41)
  - Neustadt, Berkeley, Mrs., 1967 (Box-folder 8: 42)
  - Nimbkar, Jai, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 43)
  - North, Robert C., 1958 (Box-folder 8: 44)
  - Northey, Stanley, 1966 (Box-folder 8: 45)
  - Nostrand, Howard Lee, 1949 (Box-folder 8: 46)
  - Notter, Harley, 1949 (Box-folder 8: 47)
  - O'Brien, Farley, Mrs., 1965 (Box-folder 8: 48)
  - Odegard, Peter H., 1949 (Box-folder 8: 49)
  - O'Leary, Thomas J., 1949 (Box-folder 8: 50)
  - Olitt, Raymond, P. C. V., 1967 (Box-folder 8: 51)
  - Olney, Warren, III, 1966 (Box-folder 8: 52)
  - O'Neill, Janet, 1949 (Box-folder 8: 53)
  - Opler, Marvin, 1949 (Box-folder 8: 54)
  - Oppenheim, Felix, 1954-1955 (Box-folder 8: 55)
  - Otto, Frieda, 1951 (Box-folder 8: 56)
  - Packard, David, Mr. and Mrs., 1965 (Box-folder 8: 57)
  - Padelford, Norman J., 1947 (Box-folder 8: 58)
  - Padover, Saul K., 1949 (Box-folder 8: 59)
  - Parker, Andrew, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 60)
  - Parker, Lillian S., 1948 (Box-folder 8: 61)
  - Parkinson, Benjamin H., Jr., 1966-1975 (Box-folder 8: 62)
  - Partridge, John, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 8: 63)
  - Patterson, Pat, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 64)
  - Patterson, William D., 1965 (Box-folder 8: 65)
  - Pawson, Richard H., Mrs., 1967 (Box-folder 8: 66)
  - Peck, Eva, 1964 (Box-folder 8: 67)
  - Perry, Henrietta M., 1966 (Box-folder 8: 68)
  - Pfau?, Elisabeth, 1965 (Box-folder 8: 69)
  - Pfeiffer, George, III, 1963 (Box-folder 8: 70)
  - Phillips, Eugene, Mrs., 1966-1967 (Box-folder 8: 71)
  - Phillips, Paula, 1949 (Box-folder 8: 72)
  - Picard, Fred A., 1966 (Box-folder 8: 73)
  - Pifer, Alan, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 74)
  - Plant, David N., 1965 (Box-folder 8: 75)
  - Pool, Ithiel, Mr. and Mrs., 1967 (Box-folder 8: 76)
  - Prescott, Robert, Jr., 1967 (Box-folder 8: 77)
  - Prieto, Antonio, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 78)
  - Rahman, Tunku Abdul, 1963 (Box-folder 8: 79)
  - Rappard, William E., 1951 (Box-folder 8: 80)
  - Reiners, Wilfred O., 1966 (Box-folder 8: 81)
  - Reinhardt, Frederick, 1964 (Box-folder 8: 82)
  - Reinhardt, Paul, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 83)
  - Rice, Charles S., Mrs., 1966 (Box-folder 8: 84)
  - Richardson, H. Leonard, 1967 (Box-folder 8: 85)
  - Ridgeway, M. B., 1976 (Box-folder 8: 86)
  - Robbins, Ellen, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 87)
  - Robinson, John K., 1965 (Box-folder 8: 88)
  - Robinson, William, 1948 (Box-folder 8: 89)
  - Rollins, Leighton, 1966 (Box-folder 8: 90)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1946-1949 (Box-folder 8: 91)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1940 (Box-folder 8: 92)
  - Rosenwald, Harold, 1949 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Rosoff, Samuel R., 1949 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - Rotary Club of Palo Alto, California, 1949 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - Rothwell, Chas? H., 1940 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - Rothwell, Desmond, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 9: 5)